Elaine Lagon

Email: emlportfolio@gmail.com | Phone: 817-480-3431 | City/State: Fort Worth, TX 76123

GitHub: https://github.com/elaine-drum-female **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elagonwork/

Portfolio: https://elaine-drum-female.github.io/new-portfolio-site/

SUMMARY

Front-End Developer with extensive web development experience updating and maintaining internal and external websites using content management systems for in-house companies. Graduated Summa Cum Laude and holds a Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Design and Web Development. Currently enrolled in the SMU Web Development Bootcamp. My strongest skills are design and usability.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery
- Git and GitHub
- Responsive Design
- Twitter Bootstrap

- Wireframing
- Firebase
- Client-Side-Storage
- Adobe Creative Cloud products

PROJECTS

Bootstrap Portfolio | Github Repository | My Bootstrap Portfolio

The goal of this project was to create a portfolio website using Bootstrap's framework.

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

RPG Game | Github Repository | RPG Game

Endless fighting between user created characters.

• HTML, CSS, AJAX Request, APIs, ¡Query

BamazonCustomer | Github Repository

Create an Amazon-like storefront with the MySQL skills you learned this unit. The app will take in orders from customers and deplete stock from the store's inventory.

• ¡Query, MySQL, Inquirer, Node.js

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DESIGNER

JANUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2018

The Insource Group, Inc., Dallas, TX

Client: First Command Financial Services, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Redesigned specific sections of web content to be inline with mobile first design
- Generated an inventory list of less than 500 webpage links from both public websites and delivered final product in less than a week within a 2-3-week deadline
- Provided a solution for collecting metrics (Google Analytics cannot track based off setup of intranet template) over Town Hall meetings, and CIO Monthly Conference Calls by adding a new page to intranet site and embedding media codec compatible for Internet Explorer

 Assisted the Marketing Insights Manager by writing out HTML code for a simple template used to help visualize survey collection concept, and imagery prior to sending out to Advisors

HTML DESIGNER

MARCH 2014- APRIL 2015

Digital Alchemy, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Recommended the best designer in-house by assigned clients and supervisor
- Produced a quick mockup for client and was approved same day
- Implemented an idea to the CEO to help speed up the process of building a comment card
- Launched from start to finish 25+ email templates per month

WEB DEVELOPER / WEB DESIGNER INTERN

APRIL 2013- JANUARY

2014

Nautilus Hyosung America, Inc., Irving, TX

- Designed and coded a 30 second advertisement banner at 18fps within 48 hours
- Devised a new idea for our tagline

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

TRAINING DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT

SEPTEMBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Shermco Industries, Inc., Irving, TX

- Developed Shermco U Resource Catalog less than a month with 50% done in two days
- Brainstormed and implemented the Shermco U flyer and produced draft on same day

CLERICAL ASSISTANT

JANUARY 2008- APRIL 2013

AXA-ADVISORS, Fort Worth, TX

- Entered 100 clients into the address book in one day
- Handled large file stack of client folders in less than a week
- Copied and compiled large stacks of Commission Statements to be mailed out on the same day
- Established a record since 2008 of making sure that all important documents had not gone missing during an audits

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Coding Bootcamp Program

SMU, Dallas, TX

Bachelor of Science in Graphic Multimedia Design

Summa Cum Laude

DeVry University, Irving, TX

Associates of Applied Science in Information Technology

Tarrant County College, Fort Worth, TX AWARDS

Certificate in Creating Web Pages | SUMMER 2003

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX

Certificate in Creating Web Graphics | FALL 2003

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX